Hello friends, last week I had two or three
such cases related to car insurance
in which the policy document was also
original and the accident had also happened. Well,
all the documents of the customer were also complete
but still the insurance company
rejected the claim. There are such small
things which we do not remember without knowledge and
without knowing them, we do something careless
and due to which the claim gets
rejected. We will discuss them in today's video.
Hello friends,
my name is Harvinder Singh and I welcome you
to the YouTube channel of DSC Solutions. Here insurance does not mean a paper
document, here insurance
means that you have invested some money
for some coverage and you should get your
rights about it.
Let's start the video. Friends, the
first thing that is mentioned in this is the
driving license. While taking a claim, we
submit the answer, comment and fill the claim form. So
now whose driving license is given and
why is it given,
we will also know that in this case there is one which I was
mentioning, what happened in this that the
driving license is  He gave them his own
car but someone else was
driving it and since it was within a
few days of the claim process starting, the
insurance company got it
investigated and it was found that the
location of the driving license affixed was not the same as where the car
accident happened, that is, someone else was
driving the car and his claim is rejected on the
basis that you have
presented wrong facts and facts.
Now I asked him
why did you affix your driving license? The person who was
driving the car did not have the time message.
He said that he also has a driving license
but I
affixed it only because it is my car. I am his, you
affix yours. What difference does it make?
And it does make because the insurance company is
not taking your driving license as your ID proof. They are just trying to check whether the person who was
driving the car at the time of the President's accident was
a valid driving license holder
driver or not, whether there was any
negligence, he did not have a
driving license and he was
driving the car and due to this the
accident happened.  So, you should try to give the
cut to whoever is driving the vehicle
and to avoid the glamour injection,
you should give the vehicle only to those who have
valid
driving licenses.
Do not give vehicles to those who do not have a valid license. Now let's talk about this. The
next point which we
understand a little bit is that the
claims get rejected due to this and that is to make
changes in the location of your accident,
that Malviya ji, your accident happened on one road, in the
claim form you fill it,
we had an accident at another place,
and later it is found
in the investigation when they go a little deeper into
it and find out from the vicinity, at
what time did any accident happen there
or not, you find that there was no such effect
and they say that there must be some
problem in it and this claim is a trick, it is
not real, why do you change the location,
someone might come to know why the vehicle went there, someone might come to know
at home or someone else might come to
know, they do it anyway, they
explain to people  They put it in the mother's name,
you don't have to do this, instead you have to keep the
location and time of birth as well as the food
and after the accident
you must take photos of the place, the
damage that has happened to the car, where the car
was parked, how the car looked, you
must take photos of the car, the reason for this is that
you will not have to regret it later, you will
not have to tell them that the car was parked here, in
Mumbai or in this way the accident happened, it will be
clearly visible in your photos and the diet that your
insurance company
wants to create or they have to create will
not be created in your accident,
friends, the third and last important point is
that whenever you have an accident,
you are not in that normal face, you get a
little nervous, you are not able to understand what to do
in the accident, so I give you this
small advice, call your insurance
consultant, call your insurance
advisor and tell them that
such an accident has happened, they will tell you
step by step what you have to do in it,
then what will happen that because of your nervousness
or you  You don't live normally
in a situation because an accident has happened, so it is
normal to be nervous, on
that side you are unable to understand what
next step you have to do, so you
simply call your insurance consultant advisor and say
that I have met with an accident, now
what should I do, all your
documents, all the guidance that has to be given to them, you have to
call on the toll free number, then get the
photos of the vehicle taken, what all
you have to keep,
they will give you all kinds of updates related to medical emergency, so
friends, I hope that by paying attention to these
small things, we will not hesitate in future to do any
negligence, these small things are the harm caused by this,
hence friends, I hope that the
information will be very useful to you, it will be very useful for
your friends and relatives,
if whoever you meet
needs this advice, then you must share it, if you have
seen my video till here, then there will
definitely be some appropriate officer with the hope
that you stay healthy, stay happy, stay safe, see you
next week for more good information updates  Till then say
namaskar to me.